

Freelance web developer based in London

Portfolio: thomjamesallen.com/tjallen
Email: <a href="mailto:thomwork@gmail.com/thomwork@gmail.com/thompsallen

Summary

I'm a front-end web developer passionate about building **effective**, **user-friendly web experiences**. Currently focusing on building **modern web app components**, particularly in **React**.

History

(More examples and info for much of the below available on my <u>portfolio site</u> along with various side projects & open-source code on <u>GitHub</u>.)

Freelance *Jan 2016–present & 2009–2012*

Agency: **ASOS.com / ASOS Creates** | Clients: **PayPal, Hostelworld**Built <u>microsites</u> for ASOS' brand partnerships with PayPal and Hostelworld.
Used Gulp scripts to build from Pug templates into an array of static files to target various devices & locales.

Agency: **Dunnhumby** | Client: **Tesco**

Provided QA for Tesco Groceries' XML-based banner ads along with workflow consultancy. Prototyped approvals-oriented web app with Knockout.js and responsive ad components with React.

Agency: StirPR | Client: Felix

Developed responsive HTML emails from provided designs.

Agency: Antidote | Client: Travel Republic

As part of a two developer team I created banner ads with HTML+JS for Travel Republic's summer campaign for a wide variety of destinations and formats. I also created a simple <u>ad viewer</u> to help the agency team quickly review changes & help meet the deadline.

Agency: Antidote | Client: Libratone & Sigma

Created a custom <u>player module</u> for YouTube 360° videos with JavaScript and YouTube's JS API and a landing page to a strict deadline. Assisted with refactoring colleague's first-draft JS into a revealing module pattern and added BEM and 7-1 code conventions, along with writing docs for the handover to back-end devs.

Skills & experience

Front-end fundamentals HTML5, CSS3, Sass, PostCSS, JavaScript to ES6+, TypeScript

Libraries & frameworks jQuery, React, Vue.js. Bootstrap, Foundation. Electron. GSAP, Anime.js

App state management Redux, MobX, Flux

Build tools Webpack, Gulp, Grunt

Testing & assertion libsMocha, Jest, Tape. Expect, Enzyme

Templating EJS, Twig, Pug, Mustache, etc

CMS & back-end
Craft, ExpressionEngine,
WordPress, ProcessWire, Grav,
Jekyll, etc. Node.js basics

Version controlGit (via CLI/terminal)

Creativity to make you happy

Designed & developed this responsive Grav-based blog site.

Various clients 2009-12

Designing, building, hosting and maintaining client sites for small businesses.

Open-source & side projects 2016–present

react-simple-range

Released this React component as an NPM package in Sep 2016, gaining nearly a thousand downloads in the first month. Uses semantic versioning and Travis CI for automated releases & package publishing when updates are committed to the master branch. Developed in ES6 and compiled to ES5 with Babel + Webpack.

countdown-app

A countdown timer app built with React and Electron, featuring web and desktop builds (and a truly original name...)

Part-time 2013-2015

Phosphor Art

Part-time Developer

Built responsive promos and landing pages alongside maintaining, updating and improving existing WordPress site. Created HTML email campaigns & email builder, newsletter signup forms etc. Prototyped a responsive online store page with ExpressionEngine & PayPal's API.

Stuff & Sense

Part-time Developer & consultant

Designed & built the Stuff & Sense company site with a responsive front-end and an ExpressionEngine-based back-end. Provided consultancy services to various clients.

Other work

2011

Facilities assistant at Google, Buckingham Palace Rd 2008

Office administrator at Eaux de Vie Ltd, Harcourt St (now Marussia Beverages)

About

I'm an efficient, versatile and self-motivated front-end developer. I've designed and built numerous websites from the ground up, so my wide range of experience allows me an insight into the bigger picture of building sites and web apps.

I'm enjoying using React for the view layer of web apps thanks to its composable, reusable component model, strong performance, fast development and rich ecosystem.

I'm familiar with various patterns, code conventions and style guides, eq:

- Code linting
- Common JS design patterns
- Separation of concerns eg. presentational components vs business logic & data stores in frameworks.
- Using SemVer with Conventional Commits, etc

Tooling-wise I code with GitHub's Atom editor and use the command line for Git version control, launching apps and running NPM scripts. I typically use Webpack or Gulp for web apps or static front-end / templates, respectively.

Education

Self-taught developer. The Ravensbourne School, 10 GCSEs.

References available on request